Mittsy Tidwell

Software Developer

San Antonio, Texas
(817) 301-6167
mtidwell506@gmail.com
GitHub
@ MMTidwell
Linkedin
mtidwell.tech
foodnow.site

PROFILE

Software developer with a background of 10+ years in operations management and customer service, excellent problem solving skills, and great team building success. Passionate for backend and front end development to support your company as well as your clients.

SKILLS & ABILITIES

HTML | CSS | JavaScript | jQuery | AJAX | API | Twitter Bootstrap | PHP | Python | SQL | Laravel | Fashion Design | Team Building | Team Leadership

SOFTWARE PROJECTS

Simple Simon— *JavaScript* | *HTML* | *CSS* | *Bootstrap* | *jQuery* Recreated a web version of the classic Simple Simon game using characters from a popular TV show. Optimized the app to render and function properly from mobile devices.

Weather Map— JavaScript | HTML | CSS | Bootstrap | jQuery | AJAX | weather API

Built an interactive weather map using Google Maps API. Application produces a five-day forecast for the location of a dropped pin.

Magic 8 Ball — JavaScript | HTML | CSS | Bootstrap Developed a fun side project based on the classic magic 8 ball. This program simulates answering a question by displaying a randomized answer when the 8 ball is clicked.

FoodNow— JavaScript | HTML | CSS | Bootstrap | PHP | AJAX | Laravel | Google API | Twilio API

Collaborated with a team to create a social application that helps users quickly find the ideal dinner location. Using Google Places API and Twilio API, users can retrieve location as well as maps, restaurants, reviews, ratings, images to invite friends to dinner.

WORK HISTORY

Quirk & Co, San Antonio TX Software Developer - Apprentice November 2016 - Present

Agaci, San Antonio TX — Co Manager

April 2015 - December 2015

Hot Topic, San Antonio TX — Sales Associate – Store Manager October 2004 - April 2015

EDUCATION

Codeup, San Antonio, Texas — Full LAMP Stack - PHP July 2016 - November 2016

 Completed 536+ hours of coursework in modern technologies

Wade, Dallas, Texas — Merchandising & Design of the Fine Arts

August 2003 - January 2005

- 4.0 GPA
- Active in PTK sorority
- Graduated with honors and on the Dean's list

CUSTOMER SERVICE

- Awarded for the highest scores in secret shops for the years of 2012-2015.
- Awarded the highest increase in average dollar transaction and unit per transaction for the regain in 2012.
- Increased sales and became positive for plan and comp for the years of 2010-2015.

TEAM BUILDING

- Boosted morale among team by creating fun and innovative games on the spot.
- Fostered loyalty and trust among time by using team building exercises.

LEADERSHIP

- Generated new sales tracking systems for Agaci and Hot Topic to establish sales and daily goals and communication throughout the team.
- Created several rewarding job fairs for Agaci and held group interviews on the spot. The team was recognized for the highest amount of people showing up, interviews, and hiring the correct people.